CSS grid has so many advanced features.
هناك العديد من الخصائص المتقدمة في شبكة CSS.
It really gives you control over every aspect of how content is laid out.
التي تتيح لنا التحكم بكافة جوانب تخطيط المحتوى.
In fact, there's so many things you can do.
في الواقع، هناك الكثير مما يمكنك القيام به.
It can be a bit overwhelming.
قد يبدو الأمر مربكًا في البداية،
So I wanted to try to take you through some of the new concepts and syntax
ولهذا ارتأيت أن أشرح عددًا من المفاهيم والتراكيب
that CSS grid introduces that you might not otherwise be familiar with.
التي تقدمها شبكة CSS والتي ربما لم يسبق أن تعرفتم إليها سابقًا.
These are algorithmic values and powerful tools for creating dynamic layouts on the web.
وهي قيم خوارزمية وأدوات فعالة لإنشاء المخططات الديناميكية على الويب.
These are things that include the FR unit,
وتشمل وحدات FR
which is something that's going to allow us to take up the rest of the available space,
التي تتيح لنا الاستفادة من بقية المساحة المتاحة
track sizing using min-max,
وتتبع الحجم باستخدام المقياس الأدنى والأقصى،
which lets us set ranges for our rows and columns so that they don't have to be set.
وبالتالي تمكننا من ضبط نطاقات الصفوف والأعمدة بحيث لا تحتاج للضبط.
Let's take a look at these things in practice.
لنلق نظرة عليها بشكل عملي.
These are the small things that really turn your work into something elegant.
فهذه التفاصيل الصغيرة هي التي تمكنك من تقديم عمل متقن وجميل.